FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Gmail | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | AngelList | Medium | Portfolio

SUMMARY

I'm a Full-stack software developer with 1+ years of experience creating appealing websites with state-of-the-art UI & UX using React.js, TypeScript, and Ruby on Rails, all with the ability to learn things quickly and communicate efficiently.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Next.js, Redux, Sass, and Tailwind

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, and PostgreSQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Render, Railway, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools, Spline (3D

Design), and Figma (2D Design)

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Communication, Critical-Thinking, Leadership, Creativity

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Full Stack Web Developer

Remote

July 2022 – Present

Amazon Clone — A full-stack e-commerce website inspired by the Amazon website where users can create or sign in to an account, add items to the cart, and make payments.

Built with: React.js, Redux, and Firebase

Visit Site: <u>Live Preview</u>

Lavish Cuisine — A meal-based website that gives you all the information you need about your favorite breakfast, lunch, and dinner. A useful website for quickly whipping up a well-prepared dish.

Built with: React.js, TypeScript, Redux, and Meals API

• Visit Site: Live Preview

Nethub — A movie website that displays an organized list of movies and related information on each one, A place to easily search for and converse with others about varying categorized movies.

Built with: HTML5, Javascript, and TV Maze API

Visit Site: <u>Live Preview</u>

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

July 2022 - September 2022

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on maintaining motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

CHRIST THE KING COLLEGE

Anambra, Nigeria

Computer Science Teacher (Volunteer)

September 2021 – May 2022

- Taught the basic and advanced concepts of Computer Science such as Data Structures and Algorithms.
- Improved quality of learning by introducing complex topics in an easy-to-learn manner, resulting in a 50% increase in students' grades on average.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

July 2022 - December 2022

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

UNIVERSITY OF NIGERIA

February 2019 - March 2022

BSc. Degree in Computer Science

- Worked with different people and collaborated in developing complex projects.
- Learned all programming language fundamentals including Java, C++, and Python.